{
    "id": "c0e041ddfa5c4bbdae4351d537c39f25",
    "title": "Though, Although, Despite, In Spite Of, And However",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "fea8a9089f6e4983a0a705e0dc2f9784",
            "title": "Although, However, Despite, Though",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "We went out .......................... the rain.",
                    "description": "Despite and in spite of are interchangeable. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "despite",
                        "in spite of",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "She passed the test ............................... having a bad teacher.",
                    "description": "Although is a conjunction and despite is a preposition. As a preposition, despite can be followed by a noun or an ing form. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "although",
                        "however",
                        "despite",
                        "All of the above"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "She passed the test .......................... she had a bad teacher.",
                    "description": "Although is a conjunction. It should be followed by a clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "although",
                        "despite",
                        "in spite of",
                        "however"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "....................... I had a headache, I enjoyed the party very much.",
                    "description": "Though and although are interchangeable. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Though",
                        "Although",
                        "However",
                        "Either 'though' and 'although'"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "It was a good restaurant, ......................... expensive.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "though",
                        "however",
                        "despite"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The train was late ..................... I managed to arrive on time.",
                    "description": "However is a transitional adverb. It cannot connect two clauses. It goes at the beginning of a clause expressing an idea that contrasts with the previous clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "however",
                        "though",
                        "although",
                        "despite"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "........................... the train was late, I managed to reach on time.",
                    "description": "Although is a conjunction. It should be followed by a clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Although",
                        "Despite",
                        "However"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "They managed to finish the job .......................... there was no one to help them.",
                    "description": "Though and although are conjunctions used to connect two clauses. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "although",
                        "however",
                        "despite",
                        "in spite of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "They finished the job ..................... the fact that they had no one to help them.",
                    "description": "Despite and in spite of are interchangeable. They are prepositions and can be followed by the expression 'the fact that'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "despite",
                        "in spite of",
                        "although",
                        "Either despite or in spite of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "................................ tired, he went on working.",
                    "description": "Though is a conjunction. It can connect two clauses. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Though",
                        "although",
                        "despite",
                        "in spite of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "........................ hard I tried, I could not solve the puzzle.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "Though",
                        "However",
                        "Despite",
                        "In spite of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "........................ trying hard, I could not solve the puzzle.",
                    "description": "Despite can be followed by a noun or ing form. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Despite",
                        "However",
                        "Though",
                        "Although"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}